Hello, welcome to the next episode of Learn German in Hindi.
Today we are going to learn,
in German, it
is possible, so what is this money, when the
verb is important, then we
collect money from it, that is, for example, when I
play cricket, then I
play cricket, the important thing is called active point
and when cricket has been played, cricket will be
played, when we say
what is important that cricket will be played, so
it is called passive point, when the
verb is important, then it is passive voice,
I will give you an example,
in old Hindi movies, it used to happen, the work will be done,
now the work will be done, means
who will do what you have to do, it is
important for you
that your work will be done, right Priya
is important, so it happens like this,
now we are going to learn how to do this bill,
okay, feed me, it is
very easy to do passive voice, it is very similar to English, let's
change a little here, butter
from American, pregnancy one, but then let's make it in English, so
IPL cricket, cricket,
this plate,  What are you doing, you are
accusing Bittu and when are you
using the participle, the password has to be entered, cricket,
only what will happen in German, cricket,
cricket, so here if you
remember the episodes of future tense, how does it work on
Thursday, that is why cricket is wind speed,
participles were present perfect
tense, past, present perfect tense, you can understand
that cricket, windshield, similarly pizza, pizza, pizza, pizza, pizza,
bread, get in the oil paintings, simple to
say that I have to tell you this platform, then instead of by,
for that, and so what will happen here,
Mirwaiz subscribe is always
simple, if you understand this, passive
voice in general, we use it very rarely, we
use it mostly in the
form of display in office and
in four to five forms, I will tell you now, but if you do
not remember that and it will
not make any difference, but just because we have to
complete this concept, we will learn it, so
we go to the second mode, till now we have
cricket display, it happens the same way
Cricket voice plate is cricket boys plate
so what did I do in English, wash it,
do the same in German also, velvet is
part of it, take return wooden and
golden, see how it works, it is very simple,
this your details address model Veer Vardan,
what happens last cricket voice play
cricket board's speed
yesterday cricket burglar gas victim, instead of describing,
accused of flying, simplest if
you want to go even further into
cricket fans, pimples cricket has been
cleared and perfect tense, then in egg,
like what we have done in English and below,
instead of doing a specific of that, definitely plus the
participles why and in the end
warden warden okay so what will happen cricket
right now, cricket is the real cricket, so
cricket is gas field warden cricket its
grip in the frequency, then
cricket was displayed, so what did I do there, I
added it here, this will be
cricket wow gas field warden, it was feeling like
play cricket, that
further in just to complete the concept,
what way  Want to do, we
can use it like this also, we have taken cricket camp,
cricket camp letterhead, so in German you will do it like this,
cricket can, their special
form is cricket festival, just weldon
placeholder end, cricket congress
peer and similarly cricket cricket that gas
field, so let's do it now,
cricket cricket cricket cricket test
cricket, there is a subscribe button,
I have shown you half of the ways, but let's
start by leaving out the first part, the rest is
not going to be used, still
for your reference, if you are seeing this table,
I have given you all these forms,
you can see, but what
is the sense, the simplest is the festive voice,
when is the verb important, simply is
the power, you do not need to use it, you
can do it by phone plus do,
cricket with who is the field
important, in normal condition,
whatever the word is, it is cricket Virat and
add which is behind the participants and cricket world cup
final year, if you want to go
inside the sentence, you can use cricket
board  And you can do
spirit warden cricket ward speed
warden of the list of test cricket and if you want to
use it with the entire board then you
can increase cricket cong now the basic concept in this is
simple I hope you all have understood it,
we will meet in the next episode
thank you